Guide to the Freshman Year, Yale University, Records of the Dean
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Freshman Year, Yale University, records of the dean
1920-1964
RU 813
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
59.75
The records consist of administrative files, primarily of Dean Harold B. Whiteman, documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Freshman Year.
Yale University. Freshman Year
Whiteman, Harold Bartlett
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 12-A (YRG 12-A), Central records and records of the dean of the Yale Freshman Year.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Biographical / Historical
Following the end of World War I, Yale alumni requested that a freshman year program, with its own dean and faculty, be established as a type of junior college for incoming students. Despite some faculty disagreement, the Freshman Year was approved in 1919. Its aims were to prevent a student from having to choose between Sheffield Scientific School and Yale College before arrival at Yale and to give more attention to the needs of freshmen during the transitional year between secondary school and college. Although the first goal was accomplished, the success of the second became increasingly problematic with the changing curriculum during the 1920s and 1930s. In response to complaints that the program was becoming too isolated from the College, the curriculum began to resemble that of Yale College itself. By 1938, courses were no longer prescribed and, for the first time since the beginning of the Freshman Year, students were encouraged to choose courses in connection with their fields of concentration.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of administrative files, primarily of Dean Harold B. Whiteman, documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Freshman Year.
College freshmen; Curriculum change; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Curricula; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Freshmen; Yale University. Freshman Year
- Central records and records of the dean of the Freshman Year, 1920-1964; Series I
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2040
  Scope and Contents
  Box 1 contains indices for each year from 1920-1957. Occassionally code numbers were re-used for other subjects, therefore the indices must be consulted.
  - Indices to files, 1920-1957 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 4)
  - A, 1920-1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Addresses and articles on freshman year, 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 11)
  - Admissions committee, 1920-1930 (Box 1, Folder 12 - 13)
  - Admissions board, 1930-1939 (Box 1, Folder 14 - 16)
  - Admissions board, 1939-1948 (Box 2, Folder 17 - 21)
  - Admissions and student appointments, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Admissions and student appointments: office of counseling, placement and research, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Admissions and student appointments: financial aid office, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Admissions and student appointments: office of admissions and freshman scholarships, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Admissions data, 1920-1928 (Box 2, Folder 26 - 28)
  - Aims - general, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Advisory committee on study programs and on secondary schools, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Air raids, 1941-1944 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Advisory committee, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Appointments and assignments, 1920-1923 (Box 2, Folder 33 - 35)
  - Appointments and assignments, 1923-1932 (Box 3, Folder 36 - 44)
  - Appointments and assignments, 1932-1942 (Box 4, Folder 45 - 56)
  - Appointments and assignments, 1942-1947 (Box 5, Folder 57 - 65)
  - Appointments and assignments, 1947-1954 (Box 6, Folder 66 - 73)
  - Appointments and assignments, 1954-1955 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Appointments beau, 1920-1937 (Box 7, Folder 75 - 78)
  - Art school (Dean W.S. Kendall), 1921-1952 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Assistant dean of freshmen, 1937-1946 (Box 7, Folder 80 - 81)
  - Associate dean and assistant to the dean of freshmen, 1947-1950 (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Assistant deans, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Associate dean, 1934-1937 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Athletic Association, 1936-1941 (Box 7, Folder 85 - 89)
  - Athletic Association, 1941-1953 (Box 8, Folder 90 - 103)
  - Athletic Association, 1953-1957 (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - B, 1920-1957 (Box 9, Folder 105 - 107)
  - Better students, 1926-1939 (Box 9, Folder 108 - 110)
  - Bogey, 1926-1928 (Box 9, Folder 111 - 112)
  - Budgets, 1920-1930 (Box 9, Folder 113 - 121)
  - Budgets, 1930-1936 (Box 10, Folder 122 - 129)
  - Budgets, 1936-1938 (Box 11, Folder 130 - 131)
  - Budgets & regular, 1938-1940 (Box 11, Folder 132 - 133)
  - Budgets, 1940-1941 (Box 11, Folder 134 - 135)
  - Budgets, regular, 1941-1942 (Box 11, Folder 136 - 137)
  - Budget,regular, 1942-1944 (Box 12, Folder 138 - 139)
  - Budgets, 1944-1945 (Box 12, Folder 140)
  - Budgets, regular, 1945-1957 (Box 12, Folder 141 - 153)
  - Budgets, special funds, 1938-1952 (Box 12, Folder 154 - 167)
  - Budgets, special funds, 1952-1956 (Box 13, Folder 168 - 169)
  - Bulletin board notices, 1923-1957 (Box 13, Folder 170 - 176)
  - Bursar and manager of university service bureaus, 1920-1942 (Box 13, Folder 177 - 181)
  - Bursar, 1942-1943 (Box 13, Folder 182)
  - Bursar (H.J. Ostrander), 1943-1947 (Box 13, Folder 183)
  - Bursar (Spencer F. Miller), 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 184)
  - Bursar, 1948-1957 (Box 13, Folder 185)
  - Business Manager, 1952-1957 (Box 13, Folder 186)
  - Buttery, 1954-1956 (Box 13, Folder 187 - 188)
  - Buttery, 1956-1957 (Box 14, Folder 189)
  - C, 1920-1948 (Box 14, Folder 190)
  - Calendar, 1931-1951 (Box 14, Folder 191 - 195)
  - Campus police, 1947-1957 (Box 14, Folder 196 - 202)
  - Carnegie studies program, 1956-1957 (Box 14, Folder 203)
  - Catalogue, 1921-1926 (Box 14, Folder 204 - 205)
  - Catalogue (undergraduate), 1926-1930 (Box 14, Folder 206)
  - Catalogue, 1930-1955 (Box 14, Folder 207)
  - Central records advisory committee, 1952-1953 (Box 14, Folder 208)
  - Central records office, 1954-1957 (Box 14, Folder 209)
  - Chapel, 1923-1926 (Box 14, Folder 210 - 211)
  - Chapel, 1926-1948 (Box 15, Folder 212 - 216)
  - Cheating, 1929-1951 (Box 15, Folder 217 - 223)
  - Clerical assistants/clerical assistance, 1920-1947 (Box 15, Folder 224 - 233)
  - Clerical assistants/clerical assistance, 1947-1957 (Box 16, Folder 234 - 243)
  - College allocations, 1956-1957 (Box 16, Folder 244)
  - College course of study, 1920-1931 (Box 16, Folder 245)
  - College credits, 1955-1957 (Box 16, Folder 246)
  - College dean, 1920-1937 (Box 16, Folder 247 - 254)
  - College faculty, 1920-1936 (Box 16, Folder 255 - 256)
  - College registrar, 1920-1927 (Box 16, Folder 257)
  - Committee on enrollment & scholarshiip, 1944-1945 (Box 16, Folder 258)
  - Committees on enrollment & scholarship, 1945-1957 (Box 17, Folder 259 - 265)
  - Committees: special, 1920-1957 (Box 17, Folder 266 - 276)
  - Condition examinations, 1921-1922 (Box 17, Folder 277)
  - Commons, 1922-1935 (Box 17, Folder 278 - 281)
  - Commons, 1935-1957 (Box 18, Folder 282 - 285)
  - Corporation, 1920-1953 (Box 18, Folder 286 - 287)
  - Council, 1920-1949 (Box 18, Folder 288 - 290)
  - Council of masters, 1955-1957 (Box 18, Folder 291)
  - Curriculum, 1920-1934 (Box 18, Folder 292 - 302)
  - Curriculum, 1935-1957 (Box 19, Folder 303 - 317)
  - D, 1920-1957 (Box 19, Folder 318)
  - Dances, 1956-1957 (Box 19, Folder 319)
  - Deans committee, 1940-1956 (Box 19, Folder 320 - 324)
  - Dean, 1920-1937 (Box 20, Folder 325)
  - Dean's loan fund, 1920-1937 (Box 20, Folder 326 - 331)
  - Dean's loan fund and Dyer fund, 1937-1938 (Box 20, Folder 332)
  - Dean's loan fund, 1938-1939 (Box 20, Folder 333)
  - Dean's loan fund & Dyer fund, 1939-1940 (Box 20, Folder 334)
  - Dean's loan fund, gifts, & Dyer fund, 1940-1955 (Box 20, Folder 335 - 345)
  - Dean's loan fund, gift fund, and Dyer fund & gifts-arts sciences-freshman, 1955-1956 (Box 20, Folder 346)
  - Dean's loan fund, gift fund, Dyer fund and gifts: Arts and Sciences; Freshman dean, 1956-1957 (Box 20, Folder 347)
  - Dean's special fund: sundry deferred credits (all material), 1956-1957 (Box 20, Folder 348)
  - Discussion Groups, 1955-1957 (Box 20, Folder 349 - 350)
  - Distributional credits, 1956-1957 (Box 20, Folder 351)
  - Discussion Groups, 1954-1955 (Box 20, Folder 352)
  - Duifee recreation room, 1954-1957 (Box 20, Folder 353)
  - Distribution credits, 1955-1956 (Box 20, Folder 354)
  - Dwight Hall, 1939-1955 (Box 20, Folder 355)
  - E, 1921-1956 (Box 21, Folder 356)
  - Educational policy committee, 1920-1948 (Box 21, Folder 357 - 358)
  - Engineering counselors, 1931-1941 (Box 21, Folder 359 - 361)
  - Extra-curricular activities, 1937-1948 (Box 21, Folder 362)
  - Exemptions, 1953-1955 (Box 21, Folder 363)
  - Executive committee of the faculty of Arts and Sciences (named changed 10/56), 1956-1957 (Box 21, Folder 364)
  - F, 1920-1945 (Box 21, Folder 365)
  - Faculty advisers, 1954-1957 (Box 21, Folder 366 - 368)
  - Faculty notes: including histories, 1920-1921 (Box 21, Folder 369 - 370)
  - Faculty notes, 1921-1924 (Box 21, Folder 371 - 372)
  - Faculty notes-freshman, 1924-1926 (Box 21, Folder 373 - 374)
  - Faculty notes, 1926-1927 (Box 21, Folder 375)
  - Faculty notes (freshman), 1927-1928 (Box 21, Folder 376)
  - Faculty notes (freshman faculty), 1928-1929 (Box 21, Folder 377)
  - Faculty notes, 1929-1930 (Box 22, Folder 378)
  - Faculty notes freshman faculty, 1930-1931 (Box 22, Folder 379)
  - Faculty notes, 1931-1935 (Box 22, Folder 380 - 383)
  - Faculty notes (freshmen faculty), 1935-1937 (Box 22, Folder 384 - 385)
  - Faculty notes, 1937-1943 (Box 22, Folder 386)
  - Faculty notes (freshman faculty), 1943-1951 (Box 22, Folder 387)
  - Faculty notes, 1951-1954 (Box 22, Folder 388)
  - Freshman class officer, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 389)
  - Farnam milk bar, 1946-1949 (Box 22, Folder 390)
  - Farnam & Sachem Woods milk bars, 1949-1950 (Box 22, Folder 391)
  - Farnam milk bar, 1950-1953 (Box 22, Folder 392)
  - Farnam music room, 1953-1954 (Box 22, Folder 393)
  - Foreign nationals & Fullbright programs, 1951-1953 (Box 22, Folder 394)
  - Freshmen academic guest, 1950-1955 (Box 22, Folder 395)
  - Freshman activities committee (changed from recreation committee), 1955-1956 (Box 22, Folder 396)
  - Freshman activities committee, 1956-1957 (Box 22, Folder 397)
  - Freshman activities fund, 1956-1957 (Box 22, Folder 398)
  - Freshman week, 1927-1931 (Box 22, Folder 399 - 402)
  - Freshman week, 1931-1956 (Box 23, Folder 403 - 423)
  - Freshman week, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 424)
  - Farnam, Thomas W., 1921-1923 (Box 24, Folder 425)
  - G, 1920-1955 (Box 24, Folder 426 - 427)
  - Graduate Dean, 1920-1929 (Box 24, Folder 428)
  - Gymnasium, 1938-1957 (Box 24, Folder 429 - 432)
  - H, 1920-1950 (Box 24, Folder 433 - 434)
  - Health department, 1936-1956 (Box 24, Folder 435 - 441)
  - Health department (except psychiatry A17.405), 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 442)
  - Honor system, 1920-1929 (Box 24, Folder 443 - 451)
  - Hillel association, 1954-1956 (Box 24, Folder 452)
  - Honors, 1920-1921 (Box 24, Folder 453)
  - Honors and prizes, 1921-1922 (Box 24, Folder 454)
  - Honors and prizes, 1922-1957 (Box 25, Folder 455 - 474)
  - Honors divisions, 1928-1929 (Box 25, Folder 475)
  - House plan, 1930-1931 (Box 25, Folder 476)
  - Instruction, quality of (including student rating of instructors), 1949-1950 (Box 25, Folder 477)
  - Instruction, quality of (including student rating of instructors), 1950-1951 (Box 26, Folder 478)
  - Instruction, quality of, 1951-1957 (Box 26, Folder 479 - 483)
  - Interdepartmental charges, 1920-1921 (Box 26, Folder 484)
  - Intensive language courses, 1944-1945 (Box 26, Folder 485)
  - Intensive language course, 1945-1946 (Box 26, Folder 486)
  - Interschool charges, 1920-1921 (Box 26, Folder 487)
  - J, 1920-1932 (Box 26, Folder 488)
  - K, 1920-1955 (Box 26, Folder 489)
  - L, 1920-1945 (Box 26, Folder 490)
  - Latin question, 1922-1923 (Box 26, Folder 491)
  - Librarian, 1920-1923 (Box 26, Folder 492)
  - Library, 1925-1957 (Box 26, Folder 493 - 494)
  - Limitation of numbers: committee reports, 1938-1939 (Box 26, Folder 495)
  - Limitation of numbers: statistics and general, 1938-1939 (Box 26, Folder 496)
  - Pre-medical advisory committee, 1954-1955 (Box 26, Folder 497)
  - M, 1920-1923 (Box 26, Folder 498)
  - Me, 1925-1956 (Box 26, Folder 499)
  - Mental tests, 1920-1923 (Box 26, Folder 500)
  - Morale, 1920-1922 (Box 26, Folder 501)
  - MC, 1921-1923 (Box 26, Folder 502)
  - M, 1923-1954 (Box 26, Folder 503)
  - Marking system, 1931-1932 (Box 26, Folder 504)
  - Morale, 1923-1934 (Box 26, Folder 505 - 507)
  - Medical school, 1942-1949 (Box 27, Folder 508)
  - Music school, 1924-1949 (Box 27, Folder 509)
  - N, 1920-1951 (Box 27, Folder 510)
  - National, pre-instruction scholars (Ford boys), 1951-1952 (Box 27, Folder 511)
  - New England association of colleges, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 512)
  - New York Yale club prizes, 1921-1922 (Box 27, Folder 513)
  - New York Yale club, 1922-1923 (Box 27, Folder 514)
  - New York Yale club freshman prizes, 1923-1926 (Box 27, Folder 515 - 517)
  - New York Yale club prizes, 1926-1929 (Box 27, Folder 518 - 519)
  - New York Yale club freshman prizes, 1928-1929 (Box 27, Folder 520)
  - New York, Yale club, 1929-1930 (Box 27, Folder 521)
  - New York Yale club freshman prizes, 1930-1932 (Box 27, Folder 522 - 523)
  - New York club prizes, 1932-1933 (Box 27, Folder 524)
  - New York Yale club, 1933-1934 (Box 27, Folder 525)
  - New York Yale club freshman prizes, 1934-1937 (Box 27, Folder 526 - 528)
  - New York Yale club prizes, 1937-1938 (Box 27, Folder 529)
  - New York Yale club: freshman prizes, 1938-1940 (Box 27, Folder 530 - 531)
  - New York Yale club, freshman prizes, 1940-1944 (Box 28, Folder 532 - 535)
  - New York Yale club prizes, 1944-1945 (Box 28, Folder 536)
  - New York Yale Club freshman prizes, 1945-1957 (Box 28, Folder 537 - 547)
  - O, 1920-1936 (Box 28, Folder 548)
  - Office equipment, 1920-1921 (Box 28, Folder 549)
  - Office equipment (Inc. Bureau of purchases & stores), 1921-1924 (Box 28, Folder 550 - 552)
  - Office equipment (Incl. Bureau of purchases & stores), 1924-1927 (Box 29, Folder 553 - 555)
  - Office equipment, 1927-1939 (Box 29, Folder 556 - 567)
  - Office equipment and supplies, 1939-1940 (Box 29, Folder 568)
  - Office equipment (To Bureau of purchases, printing dept, etc.), 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 569)
  - Office equipment, 1941-1944 (Box 29, Folder 570 - 572)
  - Office equipment (To Bureau of purchases, printing dept, etc), 1944-1945 (Box 29, Folder 573)
  - Office equipment, 1945-1946 (Box 29, Folder 574)
  - Office equipment (To Bureau of purchases, printing dept, etc.), 1946-1947 (Box 30, Folder 575)
  - Office equipment, 1947-1948 (Box 30, Folder 576)
  - Office equipment (To Bureau of purchases, printing dept, etc.), 1948-1949 (Box 30, Folder 577)
  - Office equipment, 1949-1950 (Box 30, Folder 578)
  - Office equipment & supplies, 1950-1951 (Box 30, Folder 579)
  - Office equipment, 1951-1957 (Box 30, Folder 580 - 585)
  - Office equipment, 1956-1957 (Box 31, Folder 586)
  - Outbreak of March 2, 1926 (Box 31, Folder 587)
  - Office staff, regular, 1953-1957 (Box 31, Folder 588 - 591)
  - On the fence nite '59, 1955-1957 (Box 31, Folder 592)
  - Orientation lecture, 1951-1952 (Box 31, Folder 593)
  - Orientation program, 1952-1954 (Box 31, Folder 594 - 595)
  - P, 1920-1955 (Box 31, Folder 596)
  - Patrol reports (re: Porters), 1938-1939 (Box 31, Folder 597)
  - Pamphlet, 1920-1922 (Box 31, Folder 598)
  - Patrol reports, 1929-1944 (Box 31, Folder 599 - 602)
  - Parents Day, 1956-1957 (Box 31, Folder 603)
  - Permanent officers board, 1920-1941 (Box 31, Folder 604 - 608)
  - Permanent officers, 1947-1954 (Box 31, Folder 609)
  - Personnel, 1920-1923 (Box 31, Folder 610 - 612)
  - Personnel, 1923-1940 (Box 32, Folder 613 - 628)
  - Personnel (faculty), 1940-1944 (Box 32, Folder 629 - 632)
  - Personnel (faculty), 1944-1957 (Box 33, Folder 633 - 647)
  - Placement officers, 1955-1957 (Box 34, Folder 648)
  - Personnel Bureau, 1927-1934 (Box 34, Folder 649 - 655)
  - Personnel, 1934-1935 (Box 34, Folder 656)
  - Personnel Bureau, 1934-1937 (Box 34, Folder 657 - 658)
  - Personnel department and Bureau of appointments, 1937-1946 (Box 34, Folder 659 - 663)
  - Planning a course of study, 1954-1955 (Box 34, Folder 664)
  - Planning a course, 1955-1956 (Box 34, Folder 665)
  - "Planning a course of study", 1956-1957 (Box 34, Folder 666)
  - Pre-Engineering all data, 1956-1957 (Box 35, Folder 667)
  - Post-War program, 1943-194435 (Box 35, Folder 668)
  - Pre-medical: all data, 1956-1957 (Box 35, Folder 669)
  - President, 1920-1924 (Box 35, Folder 670)
  - Resident (J.R. Angell), 1924-1925 (Box 35, Folder 671)
  - President, 1925-1931 (Box 35, Folder 672 - 673)
  - President J.R. Angell, 1931-1935 (Box 35, Folder 674)
  - President, 1935-1940 (Box 35, Folder 675)
  - President (C. Seymour), 1940-1945 (Box 35, Folder 676)
  - President, 1945-1946 (Box 35, Folder 677)
  - President (Charles Seymour), 1946-1957 (Box 35, Folder 678 - 680)
  - President's report, 1920-1933 (Box 35, Folder 681 - 690)
  - President's report, 1933-1940 (Box 36, Folder 691 - 696)
  - President's report (ie, report to president by dean), 1940-1941 (Box 36, Folder 697)
  - President's report, 1941-1952 (Box 36, Folder 698 - 708)
  - President's report, 1952-1953 (Box 36, Folder 709)
  - President's report, 1953-1958 (Box 36, Folder 710 - 713)
  - Proctors, 1920-1939 (Box 36, Folder 714 - 722)
  - Provost, 1920-1956 (Box 37, Folder 723 - 725)
  - Provost and Associate provost, 1956-1957 (Box 37, Folder 726)
  - Prudential committee, 1920-1950 (Box 37, Folder 727 - 728)
  - Psychiatry, 1946-1957 (Box 37, Folder 729 - 730)
  - Publications-university, 1920-1926 (Box 37, Folder 731)
  - Publications, university (other than undergraduate catalog), 1926-1937 (Box 37, Folder 732 - 733)
  - University publications, 1937-1954 (Box 37, Folder 734 - 735)
  - Public university, 1943-1954 (Box 37, Folder 736)
  - Publications, university (other than undergraduate catalogue, 1954-1957 (Box 37, Folder 737)
  - Personnel dept. & Bureau of appointments, 1940-1941 (Box 37, Folder 738)
  - R, 1921-1949 (Box 37, Folder 739)
  - Recreational facilities, 1954-1956 (Box 37, Folder 740 - 741)
  - Recreational facilities-general, 1956-1957 (Box 37, Folder 742)
  - Registrar, 1920-1921 (Box 37, Folder 743)
  - Registrar J.R. Ellis, 1921-1922 (Box 37, Folder 744)
  - Registrar, 1922-1932 (Box 37, Folder 745)
  - Registrar of freshmen, 1933-1934 (Box 37, Folder 746)
  - Reorganization of freshman year: general plans, 1938-1939 (Box 37, Folder 747)
  - Reading disabilities, 1939-1950 (Box 37, Folder 748 - 751)
  - Remedial reading, 1952-1957 (Box 38, Folder 752 - 755)
  - Riot of 1930, 1929-1930 (Box 38, Folder 756)
  - Riot of 12-11-1931, 1931-1932 (Box 38, Folder 757)
  - Riot (of June 4, 1923), 1922-1923 (Box 38, Folder 758 - 759)
  - Rooms, 1920-1922 (Box 38, Folder 760)
  - Rooms dormitory, 1921-1957 (Box 38, Folder 761 - 775)
  - Rooms recitation, 1922-1923 (Box 38, Folder 776)
  - Rules and regulations, 1920-1957 (Box 39, Folder 777 - 784)
  - Rules committee, 1920-1928 (Box 39, Folder 785 - 792)
  - Rules committee, 1928-1957 (Box 40, Folder 793 - 821)
  - Rush, 1926-1927 (Box 40, Folder 822)
  - S, 1920-1957 (Box 40, Folder 823)
  - Schedule adjustments, 1922-1923 (Box 40, Folder 824)
  - Schedules committees - on undergraduate activities, 1920-1923 (Box 40, Folder 825)
  - Scholarships - freshman and general, 1920-1927 (Box 40, Folder 826 - 832)
  - Scholarship - freshman & general, 1927-1946 (Box 41, Folder 833 - 852)
  - Scholarships - freshman and general, 1946-1955 (Box 42, Folder 853 - 862)
  - Scholarships, 1955-1957 (Box 42, Folder 863 - 864)
  - Scholarships - sophomores (possibilities for sophomore year), 1920-1921 (Box 43, Folder 865)
  - Scholarships, sophomore possibilities, 1921-1947 (Box 43, Folder 866 - 887)
  - School of engineering, 1953-1956 (Box 43, Folder 888 - 890)
  - School of engineering, 1932-1953 (Box 43, Folder 891)
  - School of music, 1953-1955 (Box 43, Folder 892)
  - Secretary, 1920-1957 (Box 43, Folder 893)
  - Selective service committee, 1940-1945 (Box 43, Folder 894)
  - Sheffield assistant dean, 1932-1933 (Box 43, Folder 895)
  - Sheffield dean, 1920-1937 (Box 43, Folder 896)
  - Sheffield scientific school, 1937-1944 (Box 44, Folder 897)
  - Selective service, 1951-1957 (Box 44, Folder 898)
  - Sheffield registrar, 1920-1952 (Box 44, Folder 899)
  - Sophomore courses, 1955-1957 (Box 44, Folder 900)
  - Social science, 1929-1930 (Box 44, Folder 901)
  - Student affairs - general, 1920-1931 (Box 44, Folder 902 - 912)
  - Student affairs - general (also confidential letters about freshmen), 1931-1932 (Box 45, Folder 913)
  - Student affairs, 1932-1933 (Box 45, Folder 914)
  - Student affairs general, 1933-1935 (Box 45, Folder 915 - 916)
  - Student affairs, 1935-1936 (Box 45, Folder 917)
  - Student affairs general, 1936-1940 (Box 45, Folder 918 - 921)
  - Student affairs - general (also confidential information about freshmen), 1940-1941 (Box 45, Folder 922)
  - Student affairs --general, 1941-1944 (Box 45, Folder 923 - 925)
  - Student affairs - general (also confidential letters about freshmen), 1944-1945 (Box 45, Folder 926)
  - Student affairs - general, 1945-1949 (Box 46, Folder 927 - 931)
  - Student affairs - general (also confidential letters about freshman), 1949-1950 (Box 46, Folder 932)
  - Student affairs - general, 1950-1951 (Box 46, Folder 933)
  - Student affairs, 1951-1952 (Box 46, Folder 934)
  - Student affairs - general, 1952-1956 (Box 46, Folder 935 - 940)
  - Student affairs - general, 1956-1957 (Box 47, Folder 941 - 942)
  - Student council, 1920-1934 (Box 47, Folder 943 - 950)
  - Student appointment bureau, 1946-1956 (Box 47, Folder 951 - 953)
  - Student counseling program - articles, memos, etc., 1946-1950 (Box 47, Folder 954 - 957)
  - Student counseling program, 1950-1951 (Box 47, Folder 958)
  - Student counselors, 1920-1921 (Box 47, Folder 959)
  - Student counselors G. Van Santvoord, 1921-1922 (Box 47, Folder 960)
  - Student counselors, 1922-1927 (Box 47, Folder 961 - 965)
  - Student counselors, 1927-1941 (Box 48, Folder 966 - 979)
  - Student counselors, 1941-1948 (Box 49, Folder 980 - 989)
  - Student counselors, 1947-1954 (Box 50, Folder 990 - 998)
  - Student counselors, 1953-1957 (Box 51, Folder 999 - 1005)
  - Student's course of study - freshman, 1920-1923 (Box 51, Folder 1006)
  - Students' course of study - sophomore, 1920-1934 (Box 51, Folder 1007 - 1020)
  - Student's course of study - sophomore, 1934-1940 (Box 52, Folder 1021 - 1026)
  - Students' dean, 1920-1924 (Box 52, Folder 1027)
  - Students' schedules, freshmen, 1923-1947 (Box 52, Folder 1028 - 1030)
  - Students' schedules sophomore, 1940-1950 (Box 52, Folder 1031 - 1035)
  - Students' schedules, 1951-1954 (Box 52, Folder 1036 - 1038)
  - Students' schedules - sophomore, 1954-1955 (Box 52, Folder 1039)
  - Summer session, 1946-1948 (Box 52, Folder 1040 - 1041)
  - T, 1920-1944 (Box 52, Folder 1042)
  - Term Bills, 1920-1933 (Box 52, Folder 1043 - 1054)
  - Term Bills, 1933-1953 (Box 53, Folder 1055 - 1059)
  - Thomas lectures, 1921-1940 (Box 53, Folder 1060 - 1064)
  - Testing, 1944-1957 (Box 53, Folder 1065 - 1068)
  - (Ralph Hill) Thomas visiting lecturer, 1955-1957 (Box 53, Folder 1069)
  - Treasurer, 1920-1939 (Box 53, Folder 1070 - 1071)
  - Treasurer's office (G.P. Day; Assoc. Treasurer - T.W. Farnam; cashier - H.J. Ostrander), 1940-1945 (Box 53, Folder 1072)